[Music]
back we're ready to cook something
everything we wipe down everything like
it said with a
damp cloth
cleaned everything everything's nice and
dry
and we are ready to go with all of our
new toys
first thing we want to do
is put
our bowl on
you just kind of put it on there
set the bowl on
and then turn it and count and put it
clockwise okay okay
okay so we got that on there and we are
going to be making cookies
so the paddle we're going to use is this
is the pebble okay
this to put it on you're just going to
slide it on you'll see the little notch
you want to go
i need to put my hand up here sorry
um
okay it's not going to cooperate okay
there it is
there's a little notch
in here okay
line it up with your notch here
push up
turn it
counterclockwise that was clockwise
no that was counterclockwise i turned it
to the right i turned it this way yes
clockwise
whatever okay you'll see the notch
don't listen to me even she forgets
that's how clocks turn into digital
mine doesn't turn unless i move my arm
anyway she's lost the old one it's on
there and it's locked on good and tight
the bowl is on there good and tight the
nice thing that i've noticed too is it's
got
on the uh
i don't know if i can turn it
the bottom it's got the little grips
seems to be grabbing the counter real
nice
so i don't have to worry about it going
across the way here
it's not
it's heavy but it's not that heavy okay
now
[Music]
we have that all set up one thing i did
notice is that inside the pan here
there is two markings in here i'm not
sure you're going to be able to see them
can you see it with the paddle on there
i think so
if not we'll we'll put a picture in
there too
um it just shows maximum level and it
shows this paddle that's how high you
can't go any higher than that and then
there's um a little lower down it shows
this one
the hook the bread hook
and that one's way down here
so that one's way down there and this
one's way up here so
just so you know you're not over filling
it
okay
and we have decided we're going to cook
some
it's called from our recipe book
this is the second one they gave us it's
called the south fulton cookbook
by the same company
kk stevens publishing company in astoria
illinois it's by the same company as our
other yellow book
and this one is called
never fail sugar cookies
this is leanne
clannon from astoria okay
sounds pretty easy we're basically going
to be using
flour
baking soda salt sugar
cream of tartar tartar excuse me
two eggs
one teaspoon of vanilla
netflix thing tatar
what some people really
think makes the cookie we're going to be
using lard
and three and some milk
so we'll go over how much
each one is as we put them in here the
first thing we're going to need to do
is sift remaining our dry ingredients
into the bowl so in order to sift it i'm
going to go ahead and take this off
you take it off the same way you push up
give it a turn bring it down okay
so we're going to sift our main
ingredients into this bowl
our dry ingredients
and first thing we're going to start
sifting is
three cups of all-purpose flour
[Music]
okay
so that would be three cups of flour
a teaspoon
let me read my recipe a teaspoon of
baking soda
we're to add that right in there
[Music]
a
half a teaspoon of salt
[Music]
start sifting that in
all right
and then one cup of sugar
i wonder how that would taste with the
monk sugar i don't know so i could have
some
diabetes sucks
okay
and then
our cream of tartar
[Music]
we did look
this up because he was asking why and so
he asked why
do you do this it says it makes your
cookies
softer
well
i just keep associating tartar with
stuff you put on your fish sticks yes
this is not it
all right
so that is all of our dry ingredients in
the bowl
[Music]
put it on
lock it down
put the paddle on
make sure you line up the
notch
all right according to the recipe
probably on a low speed what we're going
to do
is we're going to go ahead we're not
going to mix this what we're going to do
is we're going to
put our
lard in
it says to cut that in i probably
shouldn't put that down yet should i
[Music]
because i don't think this is gonna feed
through there very well
so we're gonna go ahead and put the lard
i'm sure you could use
butter if you want i think that might
make your cookies a little yellow
colored though okay well we put our lard
in the bowl
and we're ready you can use probably
butter if you don't like lard um or you
can use crisco
um which to me would be the same as lard
no that's crisco anyway
so here we go we're gonna turn this on
and we're gonna just start it out slow
and mix it up till it cuts it all
through the dry ingredients
so we'll start with one
not too loud
[Music]
isn't that great
and
three is the speed that i read in a lot
of the cookies to start it out
and i did make one mistake these aren't
drop cookies these are
rolls
[Music]
i'm just cutting it through the
make sure i'm looking at the mixture
right now it's almost
there it doesn't take much think back
when they had when you did it by hand
you'd still be
mixing it up
looks like it's almost there it's kind
of stuck to the paddle so i'm going to
turn it off you see it did it got the
back light
and everything lit up nicely
[Applause]
okay the lord kind of got stuck in the
paddle a little bit
okay we're going to turn it on again
just to get that lump
[Music]
[Applause]
you know when
when you use lard and you
really want it to uh turn out well
you're going to want to recite the
lord's prayer
now it's on six just to keep it out of
the paddle it seems to be sticking in
the paddle on the slower speeds
so now it's making little balls in there
it's cutting into the
[Music]
so it looks like it's all cut in now
you see that it's forming
yeah in there okay now we're going to
start adding our
wet ingredients we're going to add our
two eggs
[Music]
sloppy break
okay two eggs
we're gonna go ahead and turn it on
probably at about three we can slow it
down now we're gonna start adding our
wet ingredients we're gonna use our
little spout put our two eggs in okay
and then it calls for
a
teaspoon
of vanilla
[Applause]
i'm gonna turn it up a notch because
it's starting to pull together there
and three tablespoons of milk
we're using two percent
oh that's splatted
and we're just gonna let it mix up it
looks like it's mixing in really good
it's much better you know how nice and
smooth that is and how quick
probably doesn't seem that quick
in the video
but it really didn't take that long just
a couple of mixtures and you could have
cookies
this one here says uh to roll
sorry roll the dough
but we're gonna go ahead and just drop
and press it on the uh
shoot no hopefully it won't be too thick
all right
i'm going off
[Music]
i'm going to tip it up a little
to see if it works
i'm just turning it up try and get it
out of the paddle
[Music]
oops i'm hitting my
fill shield
[Music]
you can see that there's a lot of room
left in there we could have done a
double batch if i wanted to and it still
wouldn't have filled it
[Music]
i should have used a rubber spatula
yep
all right
okay so we're going to take this off now
all right oh yeah we'll be able to
spoon it and crush it
just as if it was being pressed
okay
all right what we're gonna get now
[Music]
is a little bowl
i'm gonna put some sugar in a bowl
not a lot just in the bottom because
when we put the cookies on the sheet
what we're gonna do is we're gonna take
a cup
dip it in the sugar
and press the
okay so these are supposed to be rolled
cookies so you can take this dough and
put it in a ball roll it on the cookie
sh roll it out and make a
cut cookie out of it which looks pretty
good
but we're going to do a little
differently you can use your hands if
you want
i'm going to just make some little balls
put them on here
[Music]
try and get them
as close to the same size as possible
there's gonna be some big cookies big
cookies little cookies
[Music]
okay i'm going to stick it into the
batter that's in here just to get the
bottom a little a little bit greasy so
that when you stick it in the sugar
it gets some sugar stuck to the bottom
and then you're going to go over the
cookie
[Music]
and just press down you don't have to
press them
clear through just make them flat
[Music]
i just put it on parchment paper
something that you might i don't know if
anybody's ever said when you're using
parchment paper on a cookie sheet or any
anything
you probably want to put a light coating
of uh
nonstick spray under it keeps the
parchment paper in place
that's a tongue twister
and it goes and let's see how long it
says to cook them for
wow
it says for 15 minutes
let's
try 12.
alexa
set a timer for 12 minutes and we'll be
back
okay timer went off we did extend it we
did cook them for the 15 minutes
and they don't look too bad
pretty good we're going to move them
over here
and get them off the cookie sheet
[Music]
i had a spatula
okay
we're gonna put them right here on our
little
cooling rack
yep
all right and that was our first
batch it looks like that one will make
oh at least
what three maybe four more trays
so roughly four to five dozen from this
recipe
if you're making little round ones like
this
i think if you're gonna roll it out and
cut them
like i said it's gonna depend on the
size of your cookie cutter so so far i'm
gonna let them cool a couple minutes and
then we'll taste it and see how it is
but so far we haven't really
put this through all its tests i'm going
to have to find a
bread recipe so that i can use the hook
and i'll have to make something with
like a lemon meringue
pie maybe so i can make the meringue
with it see how this works i do have a
cookie in there we might try
it's called a whoopie cookie
and it has marshmallows so we'll see how
that goes and i'm also going to look up
online and see about where to get the
attachments probably from the cuisinart
company yeah i saw them on the site um
they may have them during the christmas
time
at the stores you never know you can get
the meat grinder um
there's the
noodle maker
you can make noodles fresh spaghetti
noodles
um
so you mix up the
stuff there and then put it through the
stuff and you got fresh noodles
there's a lot of them out there but i
just don't know i haven't looked into it
i'd have to look and find out what they
are but there's a lot of different
attachments that you can put on the
front so overall i'm fine with it um i
did turn it to higher speeds to see how
i did it did very well you could
generally see the speeds change
as usual like most appliances i'm not
too thrilled about the short cord
but i know it's a safety feature
it doesn't work in my kitchen because my
plug is way down there on the floor
it's a very odd kitchen
but overall i like it it cut the time
it makes everything very nicely
and it'll take a little getting used to
what speed to set it on
i already cleaned it it's
was easy to clean
didn't take much at all
and
looks like once i get the bowl cleaned
i'll be able to put it on there
store it maybe throw these right in the
bowl and then store it on the shelf and
everything will be stored in one place
so i won't have to go looking for it
okay
let's see
how the cookie did pick one out from the
middle
this is our cookie it's still hot
still warm
looks like it's baked nicely bottom is
not burnt
nice and brown
didn't burn
it is cooked
all the way through
yeah it's a sugar cookie they're soft
[Music]
he's not allowed to have sugar so i'm
gonna give him a little bite
okay
[Music]
i could have even put a little more
sugar on the top
yeah it's a sugar cookie
right
but
if you wanted you to
you can get colored sugars
cool and then you can put color you can
dip it in color trigger and put that on
top
all right so overall
so far so good
okay
it's good does it is it come with the
comparable stuff that that 400 dollar
kitchenaid comes with
um so far yeah the only thing they don't
have and i've got to look and see is on
the pat
see if they have the paddle with the
scraper
oh yeah i forgot about that one paddle
with the scraper on it so that um when
it goes you don't have to you know other
ingredients you may have to sit here and
scrape the bowl
that's a good idea i'm not sure
if cuisinart has it i know that
there should the kitchenaid one does but
um
it just depends
on what you want that i will say that
the kitchenaid is a very because a lot
is a little heavier than this one
um
does it how many speeds does it have
i really don't know
i don't think it has as many i have to
look into it um yeah um i don't remember
i hadn't used it in that long but yeah
it uh
i think this one has more speeds
but sometimes it's not the speed it's
the quality so
but so far i like being able to adjust
it like that because it did get it when
it was stuck in the paddle it came right
out if you just turned it up a little
bit
so
all right but overall i think it's so
far so good it's great i recommend it if
you can't afford to buy a big expensive
one this one is a lot less there's
179.99 on costco online so
if you can't afford to buy the big one i
think this is comparable
so
we will do some more testing
and thanks for watching thank you